Daniel Soares

front-end developer

+55 45 98803 1679 daniel.soares@me.com dsoares.me github.com/dsoaress linkedin.com/in/dsoaress

Profile

I started my professional career as a Graphic Designer working in advertising agencies and began the transition to front-end development between the years 2016 and 2017. Today I work developing web applications with technologies like **React**, **Gatsby** and **Next** using both **JavaScript** and **TypeScript**. I also have experience with **unit and end-to-end testing**, with the consumption of **REST APIs** and **GraphQL**, integration with payment APIs like **Stripe**, **PayPaI** and **PagSeguro** and with **user authentication**.

Other relevant technologies I work with or have worked with: **styled-components**, **Tailwind**, **Chakra UI**, **Storybook**, **Strapi**, **Directus CMS**, **Faunadb**, **Firebase**, **Supabse**, **Linux server configuration with Node**, and **application deployment on Netlify** and **Vercel**.

Professional experience

FRONT-END DEVELOPER AT MARS COLLECTIVE; FOZ DO IGUAÇU - BRAZIL - 2020 - PRESENTE

Digital agency co-founded by me with the purpose of uniting the work and experiences of freelance creative professionals focused on digital marketing. In a little over a year of operation, we served clients in several states of Brazil and clients in England, France and Paraguay, with works ranging from institutional websites to e-commerce solutions, always using the most modern technologies available such as **React**, **Next**, **Firebase**, **Faunadb**, **Strapi**, among others.

FRONT-END DEVELOPER AT IMAGÍSTICA; FOZ DO IGUAÇU - BRAZIL - 2019 - 2020

Imagística is a traditional advertising agency in Foz do Iguaçu - PR. My role was to develop institutional websites and small e-commerces for the local and the Paraguayan market using technologies like **React**, **Gatsby** and **Next**. I worked with a few different **Headless CMSs**, depending on the client's needs, and explored integration with payment platforms like **Stripe**, **PayPal** and **PagSeguro**.

FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT INTERN AT THE STATE UNIVERSITY OF THE WEST OF PARANÁ; FOZ DO IGUAÇU - BRAZIL - 2017 - 2018

Internship with the Dean's Office, my role consisted of developing landing pages for the various academic events of the university using **React** and **WordPress**, as well as developing the respective layouts and prototypes with **Sketch** and **Adobe Illustrator**.

DESIGNER AT PRIZE; FOZ DO IGUAÇU - BRAZIL - 2016 - 2017

Hired as a Graphic Designer, I started at Prize the migration of my career to front-end development. Using **WordPress**, I developed several institutional websites and modernized several others. Here the background as a designer was of fundamental importance.

Education

Undergrad in Political Science and Sociology from the Federal University of Latin American Integration (Unila) - Brazil - 2021

Courses

- Bootcamp Ignite, trilha React Rocketseat 2021
- React + Next Udemy 2021
- End to End tests with Cypress Udemy 2021
- Gatsby: create a PWA website with React, GraphQL and Netlify CMS Udemy 2021
- Figma: collaborative design from basic to responsive prototype Udemy 2021

Idiomas

Portuguese native Spanish high proficiency English B2 level